<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on sowbug.com</title>
    <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on sowbug.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 19:36:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://www.sowbug.com/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Scaling the Supercharger network</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2016-06-04-scaling-the-supercharger-network/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Jun 2016 19:36:46 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2016-06-04-scaling-the-supercharger-network/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The arrival of the Tesla Model 3 is the the electric-vehicle ecosystem&amp;rsquo;s make-
or-break moment. With the Model 3, Tesla has solved the problem of delivering
high EV range at low cost. If Tesla can deliver as promised, nothing more will
be standing in the way of EV success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is, nothing except charging.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, electric cars follow the smartphone-charging model: plug in at home or
work, do something else for a while (hours), and unplug. They&amp;rsquo;re different
from gasoline cars, which follow a different &amp;ldquo;charging&amp;rdquo; model: go to a
specialized facility, fill up quickly (minutes), and leave. The smartphone
model works well only if everyone has their own charger that they don&amp;rsquo;t have
to share, and the gas-car model works well only if there are so many gas
stations that one is always nearby.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The 3 will still follow the smartphone model, which would be great if everyone
buying a 3 had a dedicated home or work charger. But they won&amp;rsquo;t. The car costs
less, so it is likely that more buyers will have lower incomes, so it is
likely that more of them will have only apartment or street parking. Until
either EV technology advances enough that EVs charge quickly (minutes), or
until every work/residential parking space has a charger, this will be a
problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Superchargers look a lot like gas stations, but they&amp;rsquo;re not. They&amp;rsquo;re still too
slow, and they&amp;rsquo;re still too rare. They&amp;rsquo;re intended to give infinite road-trip
range to a 250-mile-range EV, and for that purpose they&amp;rsquo;re good. But it&amp;rsquo;s
likely that many 3 owners (like a few S owners today) will misuse them as
their personal home chargers. On a small scale, this isn&amp;rsquo;t a big deal; in
fact, so far it&amp;rsquo;s given Tesla some much-needed wiggle room. But on a larger
scale, it could cause the collapse of our nascent EV ecosystem. The
Supercharger network cannot be a home-charging solution for an EV selling in
the millions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How can Tesla continue to offer the incredible, indispensable Supercharger
network in the face of a huge number of new EV owners who have no dedicated
charging solution? How can Tesla continue its mission of creating a scalable,
sustainable EV ecosystem?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a proposal that aligns the interest of every Tesla owner toward
scalable, sustainable ecosystem growth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;core-principles&#34;&gt;Core Principles&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Each member of the Tesla community should &lt;strong&gt;contribute&lt;/strong&gt; to the health of the EV ecosystem.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Supercharger network should be free to use &lt;strong&gt;as long as you&amp;rsquo;re not preventing others from using it&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;The Supercharger network&amp;rsquo;s revenue structure should &lt;strong&gt;encourage congestion-reducing behavior&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;rules&#34;&gt;Rules&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For every &lt;strong&gt;kilowatt-hour&lt;/strong&gt; you charge &lt;strong&gt;outside&lt;/strong&gt; the Supercharger network, your Tesla receives one credit. This could be your home NEMA 14-50, a ChargePoint station, your employer&amp;rsquo;s J1772, a PlugShare down the street, or anything else that&amp;rsquo;s not a Tesla Supercharger.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;For every &lt;strong&gt;minute&lt;/strong&gt; you are plugged into a &lt;strong&gt;congested Supercharger&lt;/strong&gt;, your Tesla pays one credit. Credits continue to be charged even if your car reaches its charge limit. If you run out of credits, charging stops.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Charging at a &lt;strong&gt;non-congested Supercharger is free&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;An algorithm developed by Tesla Motors determines congestion. The mobile app, the car&amp;rsquo;s display, and the Superchargers themselves clearly indicate whether congestion pricing is in effect or likely to start/end soon.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;strong&gt;buy more credits&lt;/strong&gt; for your car. The price in 2016 should be about $10 for 60 credits. Revenue goes to Tesla Motors, which uses it to continue building out the Supercharger network.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Credits are non-transferable and expire after 180 days.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;example-scenarios&#34;&gt;Example scenarios&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owner who drives 15,000 miles a year, charges 14,000 of those miles at home/work, and charges the remaining 1,000 miles at congested Superchargers.&lt;/strong&gt; This owner will build up more than enough credits that the Supercharger usage will be free.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Nomadic owners who go on long (multi-week) road trips and charge only at Superchargers.&lt;/strong&gt; These owners are unlikely to ever need to buy credits, because they will typically visit non-congested Superchargers. Like most road-trippers, they will also tend to use Superchargers efficiently (charging at maximum rate and vacating the station as soon as charging is complete) because they already wanted to get back on the road quickly.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Owners who frequently use local Superchargers during congested times.&lt;/strong&gt; These owners will contribute money toward the network build-out. For example, consider an apartment dweller who drives 12,000 commute miles/year and tops off every weekday evening at a popular Supercharger. This would cost about $7/day (20 kW/h charge rate, 45 miles/day, 335 watts per mile = 45 minutes/day to charge) or about $1,800/year. Tesla would eventually add enough Supercharger capacity that the incidence of congestion would drop in this owner&amp;rsquo;s local area.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Same owner, but waiting until the battery was near-empty, thereby charging at the maximum Supercharger rate.&lt;/strong&gt; A 30-minute stay at the Supercharger (about $5) would accrue enough charge for about three days of commuting, which would come to a very reasonable $430/year in charging costs (about the same as what the person in Example #1 pays in home electricity costs). This owner might find this usage pattern inconvenient and decide instead to invest that money in a NEMA 14-50 outlet near the apartment parking lot, in which case the owner becomes like Example #1 (all Supercharger usage is free).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s probably not legally possible to retroactively apply these rules to
existing Model S/X owners, but even for them, the car UI could still display
the credit balance, causing those owners to contemplate their usage patterns.
But for future owners, a system like this would prevent a looming &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tragedy_of_the_commons&#34;&gt;tragedy of
the Supercharger
commons&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Self-imposed level playing fields</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2016-05-08-self-imposed-level-playing-fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 May 2016 18:34:42 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2016-05-08-self-imposed-level-playing-fields/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A theme develops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taxi operators &lt;a href=&#34;http://taxitruths.org/nyc-wants-a-level-playing-
field-for-uber-and-taxi-medallions/&#34;&gt;complain&lt;/a&gt; about the unfair advantage that Uber and
Lyft enjoy from not having to comply with burdensome regulation:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[We] expect more and more legislation will be passed that further levels the
playing field.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet &lt;strong&gt;taxi operators originally pushed for this legislation to keep out
competition&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now car dealerships in a few states are trying to ban Tesla from selling cars
directly to consumers, and once again they&amp;rsquo;re
&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gmpublicpolicy.com/product/public/us/en/public_policy/home.detail.html/content/Pages/news/us/en/2016/mar/0329
-public-policy.html&#34;&gt;complaining&lt;/a&gt; about Tesla&amp;rsquo;s unfair advantage:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[We&amp;rsquo;re] asking the Legislature to oppose special treatment for Tesla that
will create an uneven playing field and give Tesla special exemptions not
provided to GM. There is no justifiable reason why Tesla should be exempt from
the myriad of state laws that regulate automakers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, &lt;strong&gt;dealerships lobbied for these laws to keep out competition&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes some incredible chutzpah to argue, with a straight face, that&amp;rsquo;s it&amp;rsquo;s
unfair that you&amp;rsquo;re subject to laws that you yourself enacted in order to keep
prices higher and keep competition out.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>latest weblight interesting features of this spin</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2016-02-02-latest-weblight-interesting-features-of-this-spin/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 10:58:41 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2016-02-02-latest-weblight-interesting-features-of-this-spin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://www.sowbug.com/tumblr_files/tumblr_o1xopt63tL1qly645o1_1280.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Latest &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sowbug/weblight&#34;&gt;WebLight&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Interesting features of this spin are that it’s 2.0mm thickness (still a
little thin but operational), and two-sided (&lt;a href=&#34;http://electronics.stackexchange.com/questions/209941/two-sided-
connectorless-usb-on-a-pcb/209949&#34;&gt;thanks to Passerby for circuit
tip&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are two bugs. One, the board was too wide. I forgot to resize it after
removing the metal connector from the layout. So I filed down the edges around
the USB connector, and it’s fine. Two, part of the top ground plane got
disconnected from the rest, so the left LED’s ground is floating. Weirdly
enough, it works fine, except that it can’t communicate reliably with the
right LED, so the right LED flickers. A bodge wire fixed that, and if I
manufacture any more from this batch of boards, I think I can run that wire
underneath the LED assemblies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except for the two errors, which are now fixed in the latest layout, I think
this version could be the one that gets produced at scale.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell XPS 13 9350 doesn’t charge from USB</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-29-dell-xps-13-9350-doesnt-charge-from-usb/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2015 18:54:02 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-29-dell-xps-13-9350-doesnt-charge-from-usb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As far as I can tell, the latest 1.1.7 BIOS update for the XPS 13 removes the
ability to charge via USB Power Delivery at 5 volts. I didn’t do a lot of
testing, but I know that when I first got the machine, it did charge from a
Nexus 6P charger plugged into the Thunderbolt/USB Type C port. Slowly, and the
BIOS griped at boot, but it did charge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty sure I lost the capability with the BIOS update. I’m going to try
reverting to 1.0.5, but the machine won’t do a BIOS update unless it’s plugged
in, and at the moment I don’t have a charger.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dell, if you’re listening and I’m correct that the change was intentional,
please reconsider this regression. Some of us bought the XPS 13 in part
because of its ability to use USB Power Delivery (without qualification). And
even if the charge rate is extremely slow, 5-volt charging can be a day-saver
for someone who left a standard charger at home but happens to have a USB-C
phone charger available (like me).&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dell XPS 13 9350 (2016)</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-23-dell-xps-13-9350-2016/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 21:05:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-23-dell-xps-13-9350-2016/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are my notes about what I&amp;rsquo;ve done to my new laptop. It&amp;rsquo;s the non-touch
i5 8GB/128GB model, whose SSD is SATA and not PCIe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Threw out the Broadcom WiFi adapter and replaced it with an &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1QY6l9P&#34;&gt;Intel 7265&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed BIOS 1.1.7, which today is available only on the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.dell.com/support/home/uk/en/ukdhs1/product-support/product/xps-13-9350-laptop/drivers&#34;&gt;UK site&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed Ubuntu 15.10. I shrank the Windows partition to about 45GB and otherwise went with the installation defaults.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Installed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://kernel.ubuntu.com/~kernel-ppa/mainline/&#34;&gt;latest 4.4 kernel release candidate&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo apt-get install powertop&lt;/code&gt; and then added its recommendations to &lt;code&gt;/etc/rc.local&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rest of the customizations weren&amp;rsquo;t specific to this hardware.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there might be some tearing in the video, but I don&amp;rsquo;t do much of
anything besides code editing on this machine, so it hasn&amp;rsquo;t bothered me enough
to try to fix it. I also am not happy with palm detection on the trackpad;
I&amp;rsquo;ll occasionally be typing and then realize it&amp;rsquo;s decided to move the cursor
somewhere else and insert my text way over there. I hope there&amp;rsquo;ll be a
firmware or software update for this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My quick review of the 9350 is that it&amp;rsquo;s a spectacular computer. The keyboard
is comfortable with a good amount of travel. The trackpad is huge (see above
for disadvantage). The matte screen is sharp and bright, though the 1920x1080
resolution leads to small default text that can be hard on my eyes. The
machine runs cool and is plenty quick. With the powertop tweaks, the battery
claims life in the mid-teens (hours), ranging from 3-6 watts, but those
metrics are highly variable according to small things like whether Chrome&amp;rsquo;s
running a stupid animated ad on a tab, and I haven&amp;rsquo;t done (and won&amp;rsquo;t do) any
formal battery-life testing. My previous non-Chromebook computer was a 2009
MacBook Pro, which lasted for 6+ years and was always reliable. The XPS 13 is
a very worthy replacement.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Request: hobbyist remote control</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-23-request-hobbyist-remote-control/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Dec 2015 09:07:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-23-request-hobbyist-remote-control/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I want a device that looks nice enough to keep on a coffee table, that has a
small number of buttons, that emits well-documented RF signals in response to
those buttons, that has some kind of reasonable security story, and that is
manufactured in enough quantity that it’s cheap and not hard to find. This
would be a &lt;strong&gt;hobbyist remote control&lt;/strong&gt;. It would allow me to build ugly
devices that I could hide in a cabinet, then control them with something not
ugly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, here are my options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repurpose a universal remote. Build an IR receiver into my project. Pick some RC-5 codes. This solution fails because it&amp;rsquo;s line-of-sight. And most universal remotes have an absurdly large number of buttons.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a 315/433MHz remote and receiver. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aliexpress.com/store/product/Free-Shipping-Universal-4-Channel-433mhz-RF-Wireless-Remote-Control-Module-2262-2272-Remote-Controler-Kit/1725790_32381477987.html&#34;&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s one example&lt;/a&gt;. This is close to what I want, but the documentation isn&amp;rsquo;t great, the security is probably poor, the appearance and form factor are not to my taste, and it&amp;rsquo;s not clear whether I&amp;rsquo;d be able to buy another receiver that works with it (for starters, which of the &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/LPD433&#34;&gt;69 LPD433 channels&lt;/a&gt; does this one use? Probably 433.925MHz, but how do I know for sure?).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a phone and write a BLE app that talks to a BLE receiver. This is what all the cool kids are doing these days. But it doesn&amp;rsquo;t help me when I&amp;rsquo;m at work and my visiting mother-in-law wants to [lower the blinds/turn on the Christmas tree/calibrate the flux capacitor].&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Repurpose a quadcopter remote, many of which use the NRF24L01+. This fails many of my criteria, but I did spend some time researching how well that chip has penetrated the consumer market.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does this device exist? If it did, would anyone but me buy it?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Homemade solder stencils</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-06-homemade-solder-stencils/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Dec 2015 17:23:43 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-06-homemade-solder-stencils/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are eight new &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sowbug.com/post/133445471621/weblight&#34;&gt;WebLights&lt;/a&gt; in the world as
of today!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/488e05ad2656d50b975e54b41afa1fd5/tumblr_inline_nyyracZqQy1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did a short run of 10 PCBs (version
&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sowbug/weblight/tree/master/hardware/mfg/developer/a-seeed1&#34;&gt;a-seeed1&lt;/a&gt;)
from &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.seeedstudio.com/&#34;&gt;SeeedStudio&lt;/a&gt;, placing the order November
10 and receiving it December 3. I decided to try making a solder stencil with
my new &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TuFv8y&#34;&gt;Silhouette Cameo&lt;/a&gt; according to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.idleloop.com/robotics/cutter/index.php#stencil&#34;&gt;excellent
instructions from Cathy
Saxton&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1TuF8uI&#34;&gt;4 mil mylar&lt;/a&gt; for the stencil material. This
required a blade depth of 3 rather than the 1 that Cathy recommended. It’s
possible that 2 would work, but I didn’t notice any scoring on the mat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My stencil shapes didn’t turn out perfectly square; instead they were each
individually rotated just a bit clockwise. I don’t know why this happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://65.media.tumblr.com/b9ef840e5d6a2b79bd5d0bb9ead9601b/tumblr_inline_nyyr8jY2D71qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I figured they were close enough to work, so I used that stencil without
trying to debug the process. Otherwise everything was as Cathy said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used an old shopping loyalty card to spread the solder paste. I don’t have a
lot to say here because it was fairly easy. I shone a light at an angle that
let me see whether any of the pads were still shiny, and if they were I went
over them again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://65.media.tumblr.com/68f5bb205e8556f8671cbd175cf27c4d/tumblr_inline_nyyre35Ien1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sowbug.com/post/133444522781/hot-plate-soldering&#34;&gt;reflow&lt;/a&gt;, only one piece failed:
the reset switch on the very end hadn’t reflowed, so it fell off while I was
moving the boards around. I touched up with a regular soldering iron, and it
was fine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to throw away the stencil after these eight boards because it was
dirty. I got 25 sheets of 8.5-inch by 11-inch mylar for $14.50, and this was
just a small rectangle of one of those sheets, and making the stencil was so
easy that it didn’t feel precious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pick and place is still a horrible, horrible experience. My eyes hurt, my back
hurts, and I feel silly crawling around on my floor looking for one-cent SMT
components that have flicked themselves off my table. (Fun game: find the
upside-down 0805 resistor in this picture.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/27ebf1211fbb3b27009236e9739e099f/tumblr_inline_nyyrtrDSzF1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s encrypt: success!</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-04-lets-encrypt-success/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Dec 2015 13:52:13 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-12-04-lets-encrypt-success/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Here’s what I did to get &lt;a href=&#34;https://z.sowbug.com/&#34;&gt;z.sowbug.com&lt;/a&gt; running with a
Let’s Encrypt cert.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone &amp;lt;https://github.com/letsencrypt/letsencrypt&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd letsencrypt/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;./letsencrypt-auto certonly --standalone -d z.sowbug.com&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo tar cf etc-letsencrypt.tar.gz /etc/letsencrypt&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;gpg -c etc-letsencrypt.tar.gz&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;(scp etc-letsencrypt.tar.gz somewhere safe)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo su -&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;apt-get install nginx&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd /etc/nginx/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;emacs sites-enabled/default&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Shove in results of &lt;a href=&#34;https://mozilla.github.io/server-side-tls/ssl-config-generator/&#34;&gt;Mozilla SSL Configuration Generator&lt;/a&gt;, with nginx/modern/1.4.6 selected.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Delete &lt;code&gt;ssl_trusted_certificate&lt;/code&gt; line (not sure what that is)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change to &lt;code&gt;ssl_certificate /etc/letsencrypt/live/z.sowbug.com/fullchain.pem;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change to &lt;code&gt;ssl_certificate_key /etc/letsencrypt/keys/0000_key-letsencrypt.pem;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;exit Emacs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo /etc/init.d/nginx reload&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like a lot of steps, but it was actually pretty easy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USB Type C</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-25-usb-type-c/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2015 09:33:09 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-25-usb-type-c/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m getting close to declaring USB Type C Flag Day in my house. After that
day, no new devices are to be purchased unless they use the new USB form
factor. This includes not just phones and tablets, but also laptops.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;USB Power Delivery Flag Day is still some time off.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WebLight</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-17-weblight/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 20:14:11 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-17-weblight/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/ea687d95a3716da4797db82f947e00ec/tumblr_inline_nxzsmxjBBs1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sowbug/weblight/&#34;&gt;WebLight&lt;/a&gt; is a
&lt;a href=&#34;https://reillyeon.github.io/webusb/&#34;&gt;WebUSB&lt;/a&gt; blinky light device. You plug it
in to a computer running a browser that supports the WebUSB standard
(currently only recent Chrome builds that have certain chrome:flags enabled),
and without requiring any driver installation, it just works. Each LED module
is RGB and individually controllable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first prototypes aren’t much to look at. I intend the final version to use
micro-USB and fit comfortably in a plastic LED-candle holder. It needs to be
plastic to make it possible to cut a slot for the USB cable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://65.media.tumblr.com/5944729ee4f0a504b85e6a77efec9138/tumblr_inline_nxzssdRsqw1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it’s done, it should make a good status light for broken builds or stock-
price changes, and it should look reasonably nice on a desk at work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The circuit design was simple. I mostly copied the schematic from the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://learn.adafruit.com/introducing-
trinket/introduction&#34;&gt;Adafruit Trinket&lt;/a&gt;. I originally used the WS2812B LED module, but recently
replaced it with the APA102C, which works better with &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.obdev.at/products/vusb/&#34;&gt;bitbanged
USB&lt;/a&gt; on a small microcontroller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The device should cost about $2.50 to manufacture in quantity. It would be
cool if &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.aliexpress.com/&#34;&gt;AliExpress&lt;/a&gt; manufacturers started
building it and selling it dirt-cheap; then everyone who wanted one would have
a status light on their desk.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hot Plate Soldering</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-17-hot-plate-soldering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 19:57:14 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-17-hot-plate-soldering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All the articles on the web are true. It’s possible to do high-quality SMD
soldering at home. And it’s easy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, acquire materials. Get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1ltUzID&#34;&gt;$14 hot plate&lt;/a&gt; and a
&lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1S39VOF&#34;&gt;$12 syringe of &lt;sup&gt;63&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;37&lt;/sub&gt; solder paste&lt;/a&gt;. Then if you don’t
have one already, get a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1ltUFQG&#34;&gt;multimeter with a temperature
probe&lt;/a&gt;. Next, I recommend a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1ltULaO&#34;&gt;roll of Kapton
tape&lt;/a&gt;. And then finally, find some PCBs and surface-
mount parts for practice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://65.media.tumblr.com/2cfe02f909228464998106d83f01802d/tumblr_inline_nxzs9lzB4X1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for the actual soldering. Squeeze a tiny bit of solder paste onto each pad
on the PCB, then with some &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1S3aEzw&#34;&gt;tweezers&lt;/a&gt;, place each SMT
component where it belongs. I use a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1ltUYuL&#34;&gt;headband
magnifier&lt;/a&gt; (2X, 10-inch) so I can see what’s going on.
Don’t worry too much about getting the parts exactly straight; as long as
they’re touching the paste, they’ll be good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://66.media.tumblr.com/8b2e417c169d69aa555072436083b179/tumblr_inline_nxzsa4Ba4B1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you’re ready, tape the temperature probe onto one of the PCBs. If there’s
no room, then use a scrap PCB. Turn on the multimeter and make sure it’s
reading the temperature in Celsius. Set the PCBs on the hot plate. Turn the
hot plate on to warm (the lowest setting). Watch the temperature go up. It
should take maybe two minutes to get to around 160 degrees (again, that’s
Celsius).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now turn off the hot plate. The temperature should keep going up, and around
175 degrees (actually 183 for &lt;sup&gt;63&lt;/sup&gt;&amp;frasl;&lt;sub&gt;37&lt;/sub&gt;, but my probe was probably slightly raised
off the PCB) you should see the solder paste suddenly turn shiny. Because you
already turned off the hot plate, the rate of heating should slow down and
then start going down. This is good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually the solder will become dull. By now you’ve burned yourself at least
once, so you’ll remember to pick the PCBs up off the hot plate with the
tweezers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/02e7744961c77806f4eae326c15d85c9/tumblr_inline_nxzsaursVh1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Examine with a magnifying glass or &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1S3cgt4&#34;&gt;loupe&lt;/a&gt;. You will
probably be very happy with the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SMD Rework Station Works!</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-17-smd-rework-station-works/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Nov 2015 19:29:57 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-11-17-smd-rework-station-works/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I got a &lt;a href=&#34;http://amzn.to/1ltUgxE&#34;&gt;$58 Hot Air Rework Station&lt;/a&gt; tonight, after
obsolete WebLight prototypes were building up on my work bench as I was
running out of ATtiny85s. Here’s the successful result.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://67.media.tumblr.com/2ecdfe47d30368f95f9bfda1ba7ad62d/tumblr_inline_nxzr19l7NX1qjj3vh_540.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TP-Link TL-WR703N configurations</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-10-28-tp-link-tl-wr703n-configurations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Oct 2015 19:02:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-10-28-tp-link-tl-wr703n-configurations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Two of them are &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sowbug/703n&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. They’re both useful.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>any idea on how to config the Eth0 on a 3com  Audrey? thanks</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-10-20-any-idea-on-how-to-config-the-eth0-on-a-3com/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 16:48:18 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-10-20-any-idea-on-how-to-config-the-eth0-on-a-3com/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;No, sorry. I haven’t played around with the Audrey since 2001.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huge thanks for allowing others to use your code to run G35 Christmas lights. I do have one question I hope you can help me out with. I am unable to use six strings of 50 lights. They enumerate and complete a test pattern but the programs wont run correctly, usually just the first string will run. If I use just five strings everything works great. Tried an Arduino Uno and a Mega2560.</title>
      <link>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-10-20-huge-thanks-for-allowing-others-to-use-your-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Oct 2015 16:48:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.sowbug.com/post/2015-10-20-huge-thanks-for-allowing-others-to-use-your-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m 99% sure that the problem is that 50 x 6 is greater than 255, which is the
highest value of an unsigned 8-bit octet. The G35 protocol wasn’t designed for
really long strings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You’re next going to ask why the test patterns run. I’m 1% sure it’s because
you’re hitting memory limits with the 328p. The test patterns are algorithmic
and don’t consume per-light memory, but most of the patterns do allocate a
certain number of bytes per light.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good luck!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>